

  <othercredit role="proofreader">
    <firstname>FIX</firstname>
    <surname>ME!</surname>
  </othercredit>
  <othercredit role="illustrator">
    <firstname>Rebecca</firstname>
    <surname>Demarest</surname>
  </othercredit>

  <!-- All rights reserved. -->

  <publisher>
    <publishername>O’Reilly Media, Inc.    </publishername>
    <address format="linespecific">
      <street>1005 Gravenstein Highway North</street>
      <city>Sebastopol</city>
      <state>CA</state>
      <postcode>95472</postcode>
    </address>
  </publisher>

  <legalnotice role="printlocation">
    <para>Printed in the United States of America.</para>
  </legalnotice>

  <legalnotice role="printer">
    <para>[?]</para>
  </legalnotice>

  <legalnotice role="use">
    <para>O’Reilly books may be purchased for educational, business, or sales promotional use. Online editions are also available for most 
          titles (<ulink role="orm:hideurl:ital" url="http://safaribooksonline.com">http://safaribooksonline.com</ulink>). For more information, contact our corporate/institutional sales department:
          800-998-9938 or <phrase role="keep-together"><email>corporate@oreilly.com</email></phrase>.</para>
  </legalnotice>

  <legalnotice role="trademarks">
    <para>Nutshell Handbook, the Nutshell Handbook logo, and the O’Reilly logo
          are registered trademarks of O’Reilly Media, Inc. !!FILL THIS IN!!
          and related trade dress are trademarks of O’Reilly Media, Inc.    </para>
    <para>Many of the designations used by manufacturers and sellers to distinguish
          their products are claimed as trademarks. Where those designations appear
          in this book, and O’Reilly Media, Inc. was aware of a trademark claim,
          the designations have been printed in caps or initial caps.    </para>
  </legalnotice>

  <legalnotice role="damages">
    <para>While every precaution has been taken in the preparation of this book,
        the publisher and authors assume no responsibility for errors or omissions, 
        or for damages resulting from the use of the information contained herein.</para>
  </legalnotice>
<isbn>9781449358549</isbn><edition>1</edition><author><firstname>Clinton</firstname><surname>Gormley</surname><authorblurb><para>Clinton Gormley was the first user of Elasticsearch and wrote the Perl API back in 2010. When Elasticsearch formed a company in 2012, he joined as a developer and the maintainer of the Perl modules. Now Clinton spends a lot of his time designing the user interfaces and speaking and writing about Elasticsearch. He studied medicine at UCT in Cape Town and lives in Barcelona.</para></authorblurb></author><author><firstname>Zachary</firstname><surname>Tong</surname><authorblurb><para>Zachary Tong has been working with Elasticsearch since 2011. During that time, he has written a number of tutorials to help beginners start using Elasticsearch. Zach is now a developer at Elasticsearch and maintains the PHP client, gives trainings and helps customers manage clusters in production. He studied biology at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute and now lives in South Carolina.</para></authorblurb></author><editor><firstname>Mike</firstname><surname>Loukides</surname></editor><editor><firstname>Brian</firstname><surname>Anderson</surname></editor><copyright><year>2010</year><holder>O’Reilly Media    </holder></copyright><editor role="production"><firstname>Shiny</firstname><surname>Kalapurakkel</surname></editor><editor role="copy"><firstname/><surname/></editor><othercredit role="indexer"><firstname/><surname/></othercredit><othercredit role="coverdesigner"><firstname>Karen</firstname><surname>Montgomery</surname></othercredit><othercredit role="interiordesigner"><firstname>David</firstname><surname>Futato</surname></othercredit><printhistory><formalpara><title>First Edition</title><para>December, 2014</para></formalpara></printhistory><revhistory><revision><date>YYYY-MM-DD</date><revremark>First release</revremark></revision></revhistory>
